[
  {
    "questionText": "When do we recommend students to find recommendation letter writers?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Start of sophomore year",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "End of sophomore year",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Start of junior year",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "End of junior year",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Start of senior year",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "d",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "LOR"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "True or False. 85% of the U.S schools accept 50% of more of their applicants.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "true",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "false",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What is one way we recommend 9th graders begin to prepare for college entrance exams?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Read as much as possible",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Take SAT/ACT Practice Exams",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Watch Netflix",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Finding an administrator willing to take bribes",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "exam"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When would a student typically take the PSAT?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Sophomore Year-Spring",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Junior Year-Fall",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Junior Year-Spring",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Senior Year-Fall",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "exam"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When do we recommend students take the SAT/ACT for the first time?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "End of Sophomore Year",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Start of Junior Year",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "End of Junior Year",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Start of Senior Year",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "exam"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How long are PSAT, SAT, and ACT scores valid for?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "1 year",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "2 years",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "3 years",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4 years",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "5 years",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "e",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "exam"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "How should a student pick a list of schools to apply for?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "solely based on rankings",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "based on academic, financial, and socio-emotional fit",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "solely based on geographical preference",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "based on wherever their friends are applying to",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "based on their favorite celebrity's alma maters.",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "After high school graduation, students should be expected to begin a 4-year college.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "True.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "False",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "In order to secure the student's spot at the school, it is typically required for the student to ____________ by May 1..",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "buy school merch and upload a picture to social media",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "submit their intent to enroll",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "submit their intent to enroll and pay an enrollment deposit",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "update their college information on Facebook",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "letter",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which of the following is not a summer enrichment activity?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "part-time job",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "attending a summer camp",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "reading the school's required summer reading book",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "volunteering at a clinic",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "being a camp counselor",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Students can only apply for scholarships in their senior year.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "true",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "false",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which is an example of a public university?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "New York University.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "University of Pennsylvania.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "University of Florida",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "University of Tampa",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "The Ivy League comprises of Harvard, UPenn, Columbia, Princeton, Cornell, Yale, Brown, and __________.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "UChicago",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "New York University",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Emory University",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Dartmouth College",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Boston University",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "d",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "Which is not an example of an HBCU?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Howard University",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Florida International University",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Clark Atlanta University",
        "val": "c"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What are the types of postsecondary schools",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "4-Year Colleges & Universities",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4-Year Colleges & Universities and Community Colleges",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Community College, Vocational Schools, Technical Schools",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4-Year Colleges & Universities, Community College, and Technical/Vocational Schools",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "d",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A student's doubting their chances of getting into their reach schools. The student decides there's not a point in applying anymore.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "True. The student shouldn't waste their resources on something that isn't going to happen.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "False. Remind students that it's better to apply and hold on to that chance than rather what if.",
        "val": "b"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "b",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "When should a student start talking to their guidance counselor about college?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "Freshman year/9th grade.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Sophomore year/10th grade.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Junior year/11th grade.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "Senior year/12 grade",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "What safety + match + reach model do we recommend to our students?",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "2+4+2",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "3+5+1",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "1+7+1",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "4+2+2",
        "val": "d"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "a",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "type"
  },
  {
    "questionText": "A students get accepted into 3 universities. Hooray! The student should avoid making their final decision based on _________.",
    "possibleAnswers": [
      {
        "txt": "The school's distance from home.",
        "val": "a"
      },
      {
        "txt": "The school's financial aid package.",
        "val": "b"
      },
      {
        "txt": "All of their friends are attending a certain school, even though it doesn't have the majors the student is interested in.",
        "val": "c"
      },
      {
        "txt": "The school's demographics.",
        "val": "d"
      },
      {
        "txt": "The amount of school spirit on campus.",
        "val": "e"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "c",
    "category": "planning",
    "subcategory": "basic"
  }
]
